<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Plan on sikkerhet.bouvet.no</title><link>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/</link><description>Recent content in Plan on sikkerhet.bouvet.no</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Roles and responsibilities</title><link>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/roles-and-responsibilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/roles-and-responsibilities/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bouvet conducts development projects in many different ways, where we take more or less responsibility for project management, planning, development, quality assurance, and not least the operation and management of the solution. We also involve our own, the client&amp;rsquo;s, and third-party equipment both during development and management of the solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of how the project is executed, it is important that we are aware of how responsibilities are divided. This should be regulated in the agreement with the client, so we must ensure that we:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data and Classification</title><link>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/data-and-classification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/data-and-classification/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="classification">Classification&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#classification" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most organizations have routines and processes for data classification, typically distinguishing between these or similar levels:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Internal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confidential&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Restricted&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Depending on this classification, there may be different requirements for securing data. Open data typically has no restrictions, while data classified as &amp;ldquo;restricted&amp;rdquo; may have limitations such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>strict requirements for access&lt;/li>
&lt;li>information can only be processed or stored in approved systems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>requires multi-factor authentication before access&lt;/li>
&lt;li>has restrictions regarding the use of cloud services or the geographical location of where data is stored&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This needs to be clarified with the client at the start of the project to ensure compliance. If the client does not use data classifications, one should still assess the sensitivity of the data to be processed to ensure that necessary measures are implemented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Business Continuity</title><link>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/business-continuity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/business-continuity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Business Continuity Planning&lt;/em> is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> an IT-technical subject. But it is our responsibility as suppliers of an IT system to remind the customer that the system can become unavailable.
The answer from this planning will help describe the requirements for the solution&amp;rsquo;s robustness and security level, and is crucial for finding the right balance of cost and performance for the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here it is important to consider&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The criticality of the solution&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Possible workarounds if the solution is unavailable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consequences or extra work resulting from unavailability or when the solution becomes available again.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="customer-expectations">Customer Expectations&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#customer-expectations" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Do we have a Service Level Agreement with the customer that regulates uptime, availability, and similar, or does the customer have implicit expectations for this?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tools Used in Deliveries</title><link>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>All development teams use various tools in the development process, and the selection will vary from team to team depending on personal preferences, technology choices, system and customer requirements, and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A typical team will use some form of&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_development_environment">IDE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a version control system for the code, typically &lt;em>git&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a tool for &lt;a href="https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/deploy/cicd/">CI/CD&lt;/a> that can perform various tasks related to building, testing, or deployment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>other services managed or consumed by the team, e.g., messaging services, file transfer services, or similar&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These tools can significantly impact security and quality in deliveries, so it is important that the team considers how these are configured.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Checkpoints</title><link>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/security-checkpoints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrish.github.io/sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/security-checkpoints/</guid><description>&lt;p>Depending on the security level a delivery aims to achieve, it may be necessary to define mechanisms for assessing security at fixed points in the development cycle, known as security checkpoints.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These can be defined between logical phases in the project, for example, between the design and development phases, or when transitioning from development to the first release in production. Other and additional checkpoints can also be defined, entirely depending on the requirements the delivery team must adhere to.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>