<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Manage on Sikkerhet.bouvet.no - For Security Champions in Bouvet</title><link>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/</link><description>Recent content in Manage on Sikkerhet.bouvet.no - For Security Champions in Bouvet</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Verify the Design</title><link>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/verify-the-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/verify-the-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>When we create a &lt;a href="https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/design/system-diagrams-and-drawings/">design&lt;/a> for a new solution, there may be details we do not know, or unexpected complications may arise during implementation. This can result in the original design deviating from the final solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Documentation is crucial for understanding how a solution is set up and how it works, especially if an incident occurs that requires redeployment or disaster recovery. To ensure that the gap between documentation and the final product is not too large, we should always validate the design afterward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Audit or Review of Project or Delivery</title><link>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/audit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/audit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not all deliveries are subject to audits or reviews from the customer&amp;rsquo;s side. This typically applies to deliveries where Bouvet has taken the lead, and the customer receives a solution without being heavily involved in the project&amp;rsquo;s operations. An audit is a tool the customer can use to ensure that Bouvet has done the job as agreed, giving the customer the opportunity to review our routines and work processes to ensure we have delivered as expected.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Logging and Monitoring</title><link>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/logging-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/logging-monitoring/</guid><description>&lt;p>Regardless of where a solution is deployed, we should ensure that it is monitored. Even if it is only available on the intranet with only internal users working from approved devices over VPN, logging information is important if one of these is compromised. A typical DevOps team will collect some information to help debug the application&amp;rsquo;s functionality, but we also need other information to assess the security context around it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dependency Management</title><link>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/dependency-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/dependency-management/</guid><description>&lt;p>When the team is in maintenance mode, most of the issues mentioned in the article on &lt;a href="https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/develop/software-supply-chain/">Software Supply Chain&lt;/a> still apply. You will encounter situations where:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A critical vulnerability is discovered in a package you use&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Packages are deprecated and replaced with something new that is not directly compatible with the old&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developers behind packages stop maintaining them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Malicious actors take over a package and use it to spread malware&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;.and certainly other scenarios that result in you needing to do &lt;em>something&lt;/em>. To ensure that packages hitting one or more of the points above are addressed, tools like Sonatype and others offer the ability to monitor various stages of the lifecycle, with the option to alert you when vulnerabilities or other events affecting quality occur.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preparedness</title><link>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/preparedness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/preparedness/</guid><description>&lt;p>If the team has done everything right so far, you have a &lt;a href="https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/plan/business-continuity/">disaster recovery plan&lt;/a> that tells you what needs to be done to restore infrastructure, applications, and data to return to normal operations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reasons for needing to restore can be many and vary greatly in scope. Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t run a &lt;code>delete from &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; where x = 'something'&lt;/code> with missing or incorrect parameters, or dropped the wrong table from a database? Or deleted a server or app service from a prod environment by mistake (&lt;em>I was just trying to fix something quickly&amp;hellip;&lt;/em>). In such cases, recovery can be quick if you know what went wrong, but in other and more complex cases, such as involving unknown software errors or problems with a cloud service provider, it can be more complicated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contingency Plans and Incident Management</title><link>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/incident-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikkerhet.bouvet.no/manage/incident-response/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many people think of security incidents as targeted attacks where &lt;em>someone&lt;/em> attacks a solution by &lt;em>hacking&lt;/em> it. In some cases, this may be correct, but an incident can be much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NSM defines a security incident as &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;A deviation situation where there is a potential for loss of confidentiality, integrity, and/or availability of information or ICT services. A security incident can occur as a result of a data attack, technical failure, or unintentional errors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> In other words, an incident can be almost anything that affects confidentiality, integrity, and availability, and depending on the context, different customers will have different requirements for when we need to report and/or act on this.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>